Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Game over!
（審判）
試合終了 82対91 秀徳(しゅうとく)！
Seirin...............Shutoku
82 to 91, Shutoku!
Thank you!
（選手たち）あっしたァ！
We won three out of three games at this camp.
（中谷(なかたに)）合宿中
３試合やって３勝か… ふーむ んー
（高尾(たかお)）
やっぱ アレじゃないっスかー？
Maybe they just got lucky in the preliminaries.
予選のときはマグレ的な…
（中谷）負けた理由を
マグレで片づけるのは感心せんなー
I don't like to think we lost because of luck.
Takao, go run!
高尾 走ってこい
あぎゃっ！？
You guys who played should know better than anyone.
（中谷）それに やった オマエらが
一番 分かってるはずだ
They were stronger than they were when we lost to them in the preliminaries.
負けた予選のときより
勝った今回のほうが手強(てごわ)かった
On top of that, they're that strong without Kagami.
しかも 火神(かがみ)抜きで あの強さ
At this rate, we'll have to be careful this winter.
このままいくと
冬は 心して かからねばならんな
（黒子(くろこ)）何ですか？ これ
What is this?
It's my special icing technique.
（リコ）リコ流アイシング術よ！
筋肉痛や疲労に効くの！
It's great for sore muscles and fatigue.
（小金井(こがねい)）ええっ くっ… 冷てえ
That's cold!
We ended up losing all our games.
（伊月(いづき)）
けど 結局 試合は全敗か〜
Have we gotten worse?
（小金井）
オレら まさか下手になってる？
（木吉(きよし)）そんなことねーさ
成長してるぜ 確実に
Not at all.
You've definitely grown.
Have some more confidence.
自信 持てよ！ オレたちは強いぜ！
We're strong!
He can't do it... This guy can never do it.
（降旗(ふりはた)）決まらねぇ〜
この人は いつも決まらねぇ〜
He looks so stupid.
（福田(ふくだ)）絵ヅラ ダセぇ…
Episode 22
I'll Win Even if it Kills Me
ずいぶん熱心ね
You're working hard.
Not really.
（火神）あ いや… ただ
片したゴールがあったんで つい
I was just putting this ball away, so I thought I'd practice a little first.
ってだけっス っていうか…
Actually...
結局 この合宿 オレだけ
ずっと 砂浜 走ってたんスけど
I've just been running on the beach by myself during this whole trip.
What? Really?
（リコ）あれ？ そうだっけ？
And the game's always over by the time I get back!
しかも 帰ったら
いつも 試合 終わってるし！
ったく 何のために こんな…
Why did I even come here?
What? You still haven't noticed?
（リコ）もう 何よ
自分のこと まだ 気付いてないの？
Well, I'll tell you then.
じゃあ 教えてあげるわ
ちょっと跳んでみて
Try jumping.
Breaking        Waves       Guesthouse
By the way, what do you think Kagami's practice is?
（日向(ひゅうが)）そういえば
火神の練習は 何だと思う？
Huh?
It's not just strength training, right?
ただの筋力アップじゃないだろ？
（木吉）んー
やってることは それだと思うけど
I think that's all he's doing, but...
たぶん あいつの本当の力を
引き出すためじゃないかな
it's probably to draw out his true power.
誠凛(せいりん)の女カントクと火神？
何してんだ？ つーか…
Seirin's lady coach and Kagami?
What are they doing?
Wait a minute...
リング 余裕で越えてんじゃん
He easily jumped higher than the hoop.
You're tired, so that's all you can manage right now.
疲れてるし 今は そんなもんね
じゃ 今度は 逆で跳んでみて
Try jumping the other way now.
Huh?
The other way?
（高尾）逆？
Don't you think his jumps are a little erratic?
（木吉）あいつのジャンプ力には
ムラがあると思わないか？
Now that you mention it, I guess so.
（日向）そういえば そうだな
Maybe it's because he's good at one-handed dunks with his strong right arm,
（木吉）あいつは 利き腕の—
右手ワンハンドダンクが
得意なせいか—
but he tends to jump off his left leg.
左足で踏み切ることが多い
だが ここ一番で高く跳んだときは
右足で踏み切っている
However, he jumps his highest when he jumps off his right leg.
What?
Oops...
おっと…
（リコ）
わー バカ！ 強くたたきすぎよ！
You idiot, you hit it too hard!
（高尾）ぎょわぁっ！？
In other words,
（木吉）つまり
火神の利き足は 左ではなく…
Kagami's strong leg is not his left,
but his right.
右だ
Do you understand now?
（リコ）分かった？
あなたの最大の武器はジャンプ力
Your greatest weapon is your jumping power,
but you haven't drawn out your full strength.
けど まだすべてを
引き出せてはいないわ
For now, work on preparing yourself physically.
今は とにかく 体作り そこから
どうするかは 自分で考えてね
After that, it's up to you.
Don't forget to stand the hoop back up.
あと ゴールは
ちゃんと起こしときなさいよ
Maybe I gave him too many hints.
ヒント出しすぎちゃったかなー
ま いっか バカガミだし
Well, he is a moron.
My jumping power...
（火神）ジャンプ力…
それを生かすオレの戦い方
A style that utilizes that strength...
そんなもん 答えは１つだ 空中戦！
There's only one answer.
Aerial combat!
That's the only place I stand a chance against the Generation of Miracles!
“キセキの世代”と渡り合えるのは
そこしかねぇ
うん？ どうも
Hello.
Hey! What are you doing?
よう！ 何してんの？
It's almost time for dinner, so I came to get Kagami.
（黒子）
もうすぐ夕食なんで 火神君を
もう そんな時間か
じゃ ウチも そろそろ…
It's that time already?
I guess I should...
あっ！ 頭 下げろ！
Duck!
（緑間(みどりま)）む？
Keep quiet.
静かにしろよ！
面白くなりそうだ
This looks like it's about to get interesting.
I haven't said anything.
（黒子）何も言ってませんが
What do you want?
（火神）ンだよ？
（緑間）用などない
飲み物を買いに出ただけなのだよ
Nothing. I simply went to buy something to drink.
A drink?
飲みもんって…
Red Bean Soup
よく 夏に そんなもん飲めんな
I'm surprised you can drink that during the summer.
Red Bean Soup
It's cold, you idiot.
“つめた〜い”に決まってるだろう
バカめ
That's not what I'm talking about!
（高尾の笑い声）
（火神）そういうこっちゃねぇ！
I have lost faith in you.
（緑間）まったく…
オマエには失望したのだよ
（火神）何だ？ いきなり！
Where did that come from?
（緑間）オレに負ける前に
青峰(あおみね)にボロカスに負けたろう
Before losing to me, you were destroyed by Aomine.
次は勝つ！ いつまでも
あのときと同じじゃねーよ！
I'll win next time!
It won't always be that way!
（緑間）フッ まさか“空中戦なら
勝てる”などと思ってないだろうな
Don't tell me
you believe you can fight him in the air.
Is jumping all you think about, fool?
跳ぶことしか頭にないのか バカめ
What?
Simply jumping higher will not change the results.
（緑間）高くなっただけでは
結果は変わらないのだよ
That is only half the answer.
その答えでは まだ半分だ
そんなものは 武器とは呼ばん
It is not yet a weapon.
Come.
来い！
その安直な結論を正してやる
I will correct your simplistic thinking.
He's not just picking a fight.
（高尾）ただケンカ
売ってるっつーより その前…
Half the answer?
“答えが半分”？
There's something beyond those ridiculous jumps of his?
あのハンパねージャンプ力には
まだ先があんのかよ！？
We'll play ten tries.
（緑間）
10本だ オマエがオフェンス
オレがディフェンス
You're on offense, and I'm on defense.
If you score even once, you win.
１本でも取れたら オマエの勝ちだ
What?
（火神）ああ？
どういうつもりか知んねーけど—
I don't know what you're thinking,
10本連続で防げるつもりかよ
but do you really believe you can stop me ten times in a row?
If you're so sure you can stop me, let's see you try!
止められるもんなら
止めてみやがれ！
Don't worry. I will not lose.
安心しろ オレの負けはない
In today's horoscope, both my fortune and match up with you are much better than yours.
今日の占い かに座のオレは
しし座の オマエに対し—
順位も 相性も 完全に上位だ
What's gotten into you, Izuki?
（小金井）
どうしたん？ 伊月 急に走るとか
Why'd you suddenly suggest we go running?
What did you think after watching Shutoku practice?
（伊月）なあ
秀徳の練習 見て どう思った？
いや みんな上手だなーと 伊月は？
They're all good. What about you?
Aside from my eagle eye, I'm not particularly good at anything.
（伊月）オレは イーグルアイ以外
大した取り柄もないけど—
I don't think that's enough.
それだけじゃダメだと思った
とにかく バスケを知らなすぎる
In any case, I don't know enough about basketball.
As a team and individually, Shutoku has clear goals.
秀徳は 全体でも 個人でも 目的が
ハッキリしてて漠然と練習してない
They don't practice without a clear purpose.
That must be Shutoku's strength.
そういうところが
秀徳の強さなんだろう
Even at Teiko, every member of the Generation of Miracles had their own style.
帝光(ていこう)にしてもさ
“キセキの世代”は天才以上に
みんな 自分のバスケがある
Simply being skilled can't be enough to become a regular on a legendary team.
伝説のバスケ部で
レギュラーを勝ち取るってのは—
才能だけで できるほど
甘くないんだろうな
I didn't sense much at our last game,
（火神）前の試合では
それほど感じなかったが—
but playing one-on-one against this guy...
改めてワンオンワンすると
こいつ…
心外なのだよ
How insulting.
Did you really think I could do nothing but shoot threes?
まさか オレがスリーしか
取り柄がないとでも？
I know Midorima's defense is amazing, but
（高尾）緑間が ディフェンスも
すげーのは 知ってる
けど ここまで抑えるかよ？
he can stop him this well?
But how?
ただ なんでだ？
２人の動きに 差は ほとんどねぇ
There's hardly any difference in their movements.
On the ground, they seem equally matched.
地上戦なら むしろ 互角に見える
Higher...
（火神）もっとだ！
もっと… もっと高く跳べ！
Higher... Jump higher!
I'm sure I jumped higher than I did during that game.
（火神）今のは 前の試合より
確実に高く跳んでたハズだ
There it is again.
（高尾）また これだ ジャンプ力は
火神のほうが上なのに—
Kagami's certainly jumps higher.
But for some reason he keeps losing the aerial battle.
得意なはずの空中戦で
必ず火神が負ける
Damn it.
（火神）くそっ… もう１本だ
One more.
I am finished.
（緑間）やめだ
このままでは
何本やっても同じなのだよ
No matter how many times we play, it will be the same.
なっ テメエ！
You bastard!
Notice already, you fool.
（緑間）いいかげん気付け バカめ
No matter how high you jump,
どれだけ高く跳ぼうが
止めることなど たやすい
stopping you is easy because...
なぜなら 必ずダンクがくると
分かっているのだから
I know you will dunk.
Let's go, Takao.
行くぞ 高尾
What? You knew?
あり？ バレてた？
Do not disappoint me at the Winter Cup preliminaries.
ウインターカップ予選で
ガッカリさせるなよ
We won't.
（黒子）はい
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Damn it.
くそっ…
Kagami, you're running a little fast.
火神君 ちょっと 速いです
What?
んがっ！？
なんで いきなり並走してんだよ！
Why are you running with me?
I thought I would cheer you up.
（黒子）
ちょっと 火神君を励まそうかと
You were watching? You're suck a dick!
（火神）
見てたのか テメエ！ タチわる！
余計な お世話だっつってんだよ
バカ
I don't need your help, you idiot.
I already know why I lost.
負けた理由なんざ
とっくに分かってる
How I stopped Kagami?
（緑間）火神を抑えられた理由？
You fool, I am simply stronger.
バカめ
オレのほうが強いだけなのだよ
いや そういうこっちゃなくて…
That's not what I meant.
言ったろう
ダンクしかないと分かっていた
I told you. I knew he would only dunk.
With only one option, I merely have to time my jumps accordingly.
選択肢が１つなら そこに
タイミングを合わせて跳べばいい
I understand your logic, but...
理屈は そうだけど あいつだって
ダブルクラッチぐれー…
even he must be able to pull off a double clutch.
I can,
できるけどよ あれは 左足で跳んで
右手でボールを持ってたときだ
but only when I jump with my left leg and hold the ball in my right hand.
が 利き足の右で跳ぼうとすれば
ボールを扱うのは 基本 左手だ
But...
if I jump with my right leg,
I'll generally hold the ball in my left hand.
The truth is, all I can do with my left hand is dunk.
けど 実は 左手だと たたきつける
ぐらいしか できねーっつーか…
In other words, compared to his right hand, his left-handed ball handling is too clumsy.
つまり 右手に比べて—
左手のボールハンドリングが
拙(つたな)すぎるのだよ
高く跳ぶだけでは
空中戦とは呼べん
Jumping high doesn't make an aerial battle.
The contest between two athletes' airborne options is the true battle.
そこから滞空中の選択肢で
戦ってこそ 真骨頂なのだよ
I know what I have to do by winter.
（火神）
冬までに やることは 決まった！
Strengthen my legs and hips, and improve my left-handed ball handling.
何度でも跳べる足腰を作ることと
左手のスキルアップ
オレは
空中戦で自在に動けるようになる！
I'll become able to move however I want in the air!
But it pisses me off Midorima made me realize that.
ただ それを緑間に
気付かされたのが ムカつくぜ
That's why I was running.
だから 走ってた
All the members of the Generation of Miracles really are strong.
けど やっぱ どいつもこいつも
強えーな“キセキの世代”
Even when I got past Midorima's defense,
緑間のディフェンスひとつとっても
右で跳ばされただけだ
he forced me to jump off my right leg.
On the other hand, it means he fears you that much.
いえ… 逆に言えば
それだけ火神君を警戒してたとも
Is that really all you can do?
オマエに できることは
本当に それだけか？
１人で戦えない男が
１人で強くなろうなどできるものか
A man who cannot play by himself
cannot improve by himself.
ん？ どした？
What's wrong?
Are you sure you should have
（高尾）つーか いいのかよ
敵に塩 あんな送っちゃって
helped our opponents that much?
I will still win this winter.
それでも 冬は オレが勝つのだよ
We'll be fine if it's just Kagami.
いや 火神だけなら まだしもよ
Like you mentioned in the bath, if Kuroko grows too...
風呂で言ってたみたいに
もし黒子まで成長したら いよいよ
You may be able to beat the Generation of Miracles in an aerial battle,
（黒子）火神君は—
“キセキの世代”に
空中戦なら勝てるかもしれません
but you may not be able to beat them on the ground.
けど
地上戦で勝てないかもしれません
What?
何だと！？
（黒子）
それに ボクのパスも通用しません
My passes don't work against them.
火神君がダメなら 今の誠凛で
相手をできる人はいません
If you can't do it, no one on Seirin stands a chance.
But I just came up with something.
けど 今 思いつきました
A way to help you and everyone on the team win...
火神君と みんなを 活(い)かすための
新しいボクのバスケ
My new style of basketball.
By mastering my own drive in addition to my passes,
パス以外に
ボクだけのドライブを修得して—
I will surpass the Generation of Miracles.
ボクが“キセキの世代”を抜きます
フン！ 望むところなのだよ
I couldn't ask for more.
（高尾）
オレは望んでねえっつーの！
I could!
Breaking        Waves       Guesthouse
Everyone's here.
（日向）よーし 全員いるな
せーの…
Ready, and...
Thank you very much!
（一同）ありがとうございました！
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）わん！
All right! I feel alive!
（小金井）
しゃー！ 生きてるオレっ！
I thought I was gonna die so many times.
（福田）何度も死ぬかと思ったよ
I want to sleep in my own bed!
（降旗）
早く家のフトンで寝てー！
（河原(かわはら)）
オレ 枕 変わると 寝れなくてさー
I couldn't sleep with a different pillow.
You were sound asleep.
（福田）爆睡してたじゃねーか
That's it!
（伊月）それだ！
枕に埋もれて 真っ暗
Buried in pillows, buried in darkness.
Izuki, shut up.
（日向）伊月 黙れ
Where do you think you're going?
（リコ）ちょっと どこ行くのよ？
What? To the station.
（日向）へ？ いや 駅 だけど…
Why do you think we held our training camp here?
（リコ）何のために
ここで合宿したと思ってんの？
This year they're holding the games here!
今年は ここで開催でしょーが！
I see.
そういうことか
今日は準々決勝 組み合わせは…
Today's quarterfinal game is between...
（日向）うっ 海常(かいじょう) 対 桐皇(とうおう)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Kaijo and Touou!
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Boys' Basketball Championship
Tournament
Today 14:00~
Second Quarterfinal Game
Kaijo High School (Kanagawa)
VS
Touou Academy (Tokyo)
Let's go watch the Inter-High.
このまま見に行くわよ
インターハイ
Kagami...
（黒子）火神君
ぬおっ！ 何だよ！？
What do you want?
Just before we left, Midorima gave me a message.
（黒子）出発する直前
緑間君に伝言をもらいました
What?
Thank you.
（黒子）ありがとうございました
Don't be ridiculous.
ふざけるな
礼を言われる筋合いはない
I did nothing to deserve your gratitude.
Even a flea can jump.
あいつにしても…
跳ぶだけなら ノミでもできる
"I only taught him a lesson because he's so stupid."
（黒子）“バカすぎて
懲らしめただけなのだよ”
ほー あのヤロー
That bastard...
Also,
（黒子）あと…“オレが倒すまで
負けるな”だそうです
"Don't lose until I beat you," apparently.
ハハッ！
“負けるかよ バーカ”つっとけ！
Like hell I'll lose! You tell him that!
Entrance
Amazing! So this is the Inter-High!
すっげー！ これがインターハイ！
カントク お目当ての試合は？
Coach, when's the game we're here to see?
After this one. It should be soon.
この試合の後… もうすぐよ
Kaijo versus Touou. A game between...
（火神）
海常 対 桐皇 この試合は つまり…
Kise Ryota and Aomine Daiki!
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた) 対 青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)！
Kuroko,
（火神）
黒子 どっちが勝つと思う？
who do you think will win?
I don't know.
分かりません
This is the first time I've seen two Generation of Miracles starters play against each other.
“キセキの世代”のスタメン同士が
戦うのは 初めてです ただ…
However...
Aomine inspired Kise to play basketball.
黄瀬君は 青峰君に憧れて
バスケを始めました
Really?
（火神）えっ そうなのか？
They used to play one-on-one a lot,
（黒子）そして よく２人で
ワンオンワンをしてました
が 黄瀬君が勝ったことは
一度もありません
but Kise didn't win a single time.
...Kaijo High
Dressing Room
（早川(はやかわ)）あー ヤッベー！
Oh, man!
I'm so excited! Oh, man!
テンション
上がってき… ヤッベー！
I'm gonna do it! I'm so gonna do it!
（早川）やぃますよ… オェっ！
ぇんしゅうの成果を今こそっ！
I'm ready to show them what I've learned in practice!
I'm gonna try real hard! Seriously, man!
がんばぃますかぁっ！ マジで
がんばぃますかぁっ！ オェっ！
（笠松(かさまつ)）は！？ なんて？
What did you say?
I told you, I'm gonna try real hard!
だかぁっ… だかぁっ！
がんばぃます オェっ！
近(ちけ)えよ！
You're too close!
You're crowding me, you're talking too fast to make any sense,
あつっくるしーし 早口だし
ラ行 言えてねーし
and I don't have any idea what you're saying, you idiot!
何言ってっか分かんねーよ バカ！
すんません！ でも オェっ…
Sorry, but I...
Hey, Moriyama! Do something about this idiot!
オイ 森山(もりやま)！
何とかしてくれ このバカ
Actually, Kasamatsu...
（森山）それより 笠松…
西側 ３列目 一番 はじ
Third row on the west side, way on the end...
Did you see them? They're here.
（森山）見たか？ 来てたぜ
A super cute girl!
超カワイイ子が！
オレ 今日 あの子のために戦う！
I'm going to play for her today!
Play for us, you moron!
（笠松）
ウチのために戦え バカヤロウ！
Senpai!
（黄瀬）先輩！
What now?
今度は何だ？
I got something from my fans, but it's okay if I eat it, right?
（黄瀬）ファンの子から
差し入れもらったんスけど—
食って大丈夫スかね？
万一 何か入ってたら… ダアッ！
If something's in it, I...
食って できれば 死ね！
If you can eat and play, go die!
I can't believe all of you. Just let me focus.
どいつもこいつも…
つーか 集中させろ！
Hey, are you guys ready to go?
（武内(たけうち)）オイ オマエら
準備は できてるか？
It's almost time to get out there.
もうすぐ入場だぞ
（武内）気合入れていけ
Give it everything you have.
Why are you trying to compete with that handsome Touou coach, old man?
（笠松）
なんで 桐皇のイケメン監督と—
張り合ってんだ オッサン！
Our game plan will be what we discussed in our meeting.
（武内）ゲームプランは さっきの
ミーティングで話したとおりだ
Stay focused.
あとは 集中力 高めとけよ
Kise, come get me five minutes before we start.
（笠松）
黄瀬 ５分前になったら 呼べ
はい
Okay.
Even he gets nervous.
やっぱ 先輩でも
キンチョーするんスねえ…
Well, that's not all it is.
まあ それだけじゃないがな…
あいつは
Huh?
.Touou Academy
Dressing Room
Touou Academy
Well, Momoi? Did you get in touch with him?
（今吉(いまよし)）
どうや？ 桃井(ももい) つながったか？
He won't answer.
（さつき）ダメです 全然…
（若松(わかまつ)）う… ううっ
I can't believe how relaxed Aomine is.
にしても ホンマ
青峰のルーズさには まいるわ
We don't need that guy!
（若松）つーか もう いなくて
いいっスよ あんなヤロー！
Sorry, sorry!
（桜井(さくらい)）
スイマセン！ スイマセン！
He's been late to every game!
（若松）ここまで 全試合 遅刻！
来ても 試合は テキトーに流すだけ
Even when he shows up, he doesn't always play!
I'm sure he'll be late again today!
どーせ 今日も遅刻っスよ！
We'll be in trouble if he doesn't show up today.
（原澤(はらさわ)）さすがに
今日ばかりは いないと困りますね
They're not so weak that we can beat them without him starting.
彼抜きでスタートして勝てるほど
甘い相手ではないですよ
Hey.
（青峰(あおみね)）ウース
Did you say something?
（青峰）なんか言ったかよ？
Looks like you've already warmed up.
アップは… 済んでるみたいですね
I thought you guys might have some trouble without me today.
（青峰）あー まあ 今日は
さすがにオレいないとキツいっしょ
Don't make me worry every time!
もうっ 毎回 心配させないでよ！
We're up against Kise.
相手が黄瀬だぜ？
遅れるわけねえだろ
There's no way I'd be late.
I've been looking forward to playing against him for a long time.
ずっと楽しみにしてたんだぜ
あいつとやるの
なんせ—
He's one of the few guys I can crush with all my might.
オレが本気で潰せる
数少ない相手だからな
Senpai, five more minutes.
（黄瀬）先輩 あと５分っス
（笠松）おう
Okay.
You've been doing that a lot since the Inter-High started.
インターハイに来てから
よく そうしてるっスね
ウチは 去年のインターハイ—
At last year's Inter-High, we were strong enough to get to the championship.
優勝すら望める
過去最強のメンバーだったが—
結果は知ってるか？
Do you know what happened?
You lost your first game, right?
確か 初戦敗退…
It was my fault.
（笠松）ありゃ オレのせいだ
With a one point lead, I messed up a pass, and gave away the game.
１点差の土壇場でパスミスして
逆転を許した
My seniors' tears, their criticism.
先輩たちの涙 ＯＢからの非難
オレは 辞めようとまで思った
I even thought about quitting, but...
けど 監督は
オレをキャプテンに選んで言った
The coach made me captain and said this,
That's why you should do it.
だから オマエがやれ
（笠松）そんときに オレは決めた
That was when I decided.
I don't think I can make up for what I did.
償えるとは思ってねえ
救われるつもりもねえ
I don't expect to be saved.
But I'll still win the Inter-High.
それでも
インターハイで優勝する
It's my responsibility as, and reason for being the captain.
それが
オレのけじめで—
キャプテンとしての
存在意義だ
（黄瀬）ふーん オレは 青峰っちに
初勝利が目標ってぐらいっス
Huh?
Well, I'm just hoping to beat Aominecchi for the first time.
I see.
（笠松）あっそ
I'll win even if it kills me.
（黄瀬）死んでも勝つっスけど
フッ… あっそ
I see.
I won't lose, Aominecchi.
（黄瀬）負けねっスよ 青峰っち
What? You're awfully confident, Kise.
あん？
ずいぶん 威勢いいじゃねえか 黄瀬
Have you ever beaten me before?
今まで 一度でも
オレに勝ったことがあったかよ？
I'll win today.
今日 勝つっス
なんか
負けたくなくなっちゃったんスよ
I really don't want to lose today.
ムショーに
Good luck.
よろしゅう
（笠松）よろしく
（今吉）ふ〜ん 風格あるわ…
He's got presence.
さすが
全国区のキャプテンってトコやな
I wouldn't expect less from such a strong team's captain.
（アナウンス）
それでは 準々決勝 第２試合—
The second quarterfinal game between
Kaijo High School and Touou Academy will now begin!
海常高校 対 桐皇学園高校の
試合を始めます
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
（今吉）お手柔らかに 海常さん
Let's take it easy, Kaijo.
I don't see your eyes smiling.
（笠松）目が笑ってねえんだよ
I'm sure I'm just nervous.
（今吉）緊張してんねんな きっと
（笠松）
何 たくらんでるか知らねえが—
I don't know what you're planning, but we believe in Kise.
オレたちは 黄瀬を信じてる
（今吉）ワシらかて 信じてるでぇ
And we have faith too,
Episode 23
I'm Not Mature!
最強は青峰や
that Aomine is the best.